Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office. Marketing Vertical File, 1937-1998 and undated RL.11055
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office. Marketing Vertical File, 1937-1998 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office
RL.11055
9 Linear Feet
Founded in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. The Chicago Office opened in 1891.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically by subject.
Biographical / Historical
The JWT Chicago Office opened in 1891 by Charles Raymond.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office. Marketing Vertical File was received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift/purchase/transfer] in 2001-2002.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office Records J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office. Media Resources and Research Department records J. Walter Thompson Company. Marketing Vertical File J. Walter Thompson Company. Radio/Television Department records J. Walter Thompson Company. John Devine Papers J. Walter Thompson Company. Account Files
Collection Overview
Consists mainly of internal and trade research and subject reports. Topics covered include Broadcast and cable television, general marketing and market research, magazines, out of home media. Market research firms represented include Daniel Starch, Gallup, Marketing Science Institute, Nielsen, Roper and Yankelovich. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
J. Walter Thompson Company; J. Walter Thompson Company -- History; Advertising agencies -- Illinois -- Chicago; Advertising -- History; Advertising agencies -- United States -- History; Market research; J. Walter Thompson Company. Chicago Office
- Subject Files, 1937-1998 and undated; 1
  - Action for Children's Television, 1971-1981 (Box 1)
  - ASI Market Research, 1980-1982 (Box 1)
  - Bruskin Associates--Bruskin Report, 1982-1988; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Bruskin Goldring, 1992-1997 (Box 1)
  - Burke/AdTel, 1971-1983 (Box 1)
  - Burke Marketing Research, 1968-1985; 4 folders (Box 1)
  - Business-to-business, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Cosmos, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Direct mail, 1983 (Box 1)
  - Discover Card, 1987 (Box 2)
  - Drug stores, 1989-1990 (Box 2)
  - Food, 1986-1988; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Future trends, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Gallup, 1986-1987 (Box 2)
  - Guerlain, 1993 (Box 2)
  - Home video, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Landor Associates, 1982-1997 (Box 2)
  - Magazines, 1966-1983; 10 folders (Box 2)
  - Magazines, 1980-1993; 10 folders (Box 3)
  - Magazines--Being Well, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Magazines--Business magazines, 1983-1986; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Magazines--Circulation, 1982-1992; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Magazines--Coupons, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Magazines--Fleischmann's Yeast, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Magazines--Inflight, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Magazines--Kodak/Time, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Magazines--Kraft, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Magazines--Kraft/General Mills, 1979 (Box 4)
  - Magazines--Kraft Miracle Whip, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Magazines--Magazine covers, 1991 (Box 4)
  - Magazines--Magazine Newsletter, 1973-1980 (Box 4)
  - Magazines--Maxfli, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Magazines--Oscar Mayer, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Magazines--Progressive Grocer, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Magazines--Reader's Digest/TV Guide, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Magazines--Readership, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Magazines--Rolex, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Magazines--S.C. Johnson, 1984-1987 (Box 4)
  - Magazines--Science magazines, 1980 (Box 4)
  - Magazines--Special interest, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Magazines--Special Interest Magazine Guide, undated (Box 4)
  - Magazines--Vainty Fair, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Magazines--Vogue, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Magazines--W.A. Taylor, 1983-1987; 4 folders (Box 4)
  - Magazines--Warner-Lambert, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Magazines--Women's, 1973-1991; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Magazines--Women's--Seven Sisters, 1993 (Box 4)
  - Magazines--Working women, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Manufacturers' Coupon Control Center, 1986-1989 (Box 5)
  - Marketing, 1978-1992; 5 folders (Box 5)
  - Marketing Evaluations, Inc., 1980-1994; 2 folders (Box 5)
  - Marketing Science Institute, 1991-1998; 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Marketing Science Institute, 1991-1998; 5 folders (Box 6)
  - McCollum Spielman/Topline, 1970-1994; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - McDonnell Douglas, 1989 (Box 6)
  - New media, 1980-1984; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - New media--Home shopping, 1981 (Box 7)
  - New media--Home video, 1987 (Box 7)
  - New media--Non-print communication, 1981 (Box 7)
  - New media--Oscar Mayer, 1987 (Box 7)
  - New products, 1982-1985; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Niche marketing, 1988 (Box 7)
  - Nielsen, 1964-1987; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Nielsen Marketing Research Services, 1969-1988; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Nielsen Media Research, 1984-1988 (Box 7)
  - Nielsen New Product Services, 1981 (Box 7)
  - Nielsen Researcher, 1948-1969; 4 folders (Box 7)
  - Nielsen Researcher, 1970-1989; 4 folders (Box 8)
  - Nielsen Retail, 1972-1980 (Box 8)
  - Oscar Mayer, 1988 (Box 8)
  - Out-of-home, 1990 (Box 8)
  - Out-of-home--Baseball, 1980 (Box 8)
  - Out-of-home viewing, 1989 (Box 8)
  - Perception Research Services, 1976-1985 (Box 8)
  - Quaker Oats--Kibbles 'N Bits, 1993 (Box 8)
  - Regional marketing, 1988 (Box 8)
  - Research Systems Corp. (Advertising Research System), 1976-1983 (Box 8)
  - Roper Organization, 1983-1991 (Box 8)
  - Selling Areas Marketing Inc. (SAMI), 1968-1985 (Box 9)
  - Schoenfeld, Gerald, 1982 (Box 9)
  - Schwerin Research, 1959-1970 (Box 9)
  - Selection Research Inc. (SRI), 1980-1984 (Box 9)
  - Social Research Inc., 1956-1981 (Box 9)
  - Southland Corporation, 1992 (Box 9)
  - Starch Staff--Television commercials, 1970-1971 (Box 9)
  - Starch Staff--Tested Copy, 1937-1989; 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Starch INRA Hooper, 1970-1985 (Box 9)
  - Strategic Planning Institute (PIMS), 1977-1989 (Box 9)
  - Television, 1971-1992; 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Television, 1978-1989; 16 folders (Box 10)
  - Television, 1989-1992; 4 folders (Box 11)
  - Television--Burger King, 1987; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Television--Cable, 1971-1989; 12 folders (Box 11)
  - Television--Cable--Home shopping, 1985-1986 (Box 11)
  - Television--Cable--Kellogg's, 1988 (Box 11)
  - Television--Cable--Nestle, 1989-1990 (Box 11)
  - Television--Cable--Quaker Oats, 1988; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Television--Case studies, 1993 (Box 11)
  - Television--Case studies, 1993 (Box 12)
  - Television--CBS Basic Guide, 1979 (Box 12)
  - Television--Daytime, 1980-1985; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Television--Ford, 1983-1989; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Television--Game shows, 1978 (Box 12)
  - Television--Gerber, 1989 (Box 12)
  - Television--Germany, 1991 (Box 12)
  - Television--Godfather Pizza, 1987 (Box 12)
  - Television--Infomercials, 1993-1997 (Box 12)
  - Television--Kellogg's, 1985 (Box 12)
  - Television--Kodak, 1984 (Box 12)
  - Television--Kraft, 1990 (Box 12)
  - Television--Late night, 1981 (Box 12)
  - Television--Leo Burnett, 1985-1986 (Box 12)
  - Television--Mentholatum--Canada, 1975 (Box 12)
  - Television--Nestle Morsels, 1986 (Box 12)
  - Television--Network specials, 1988 (Box 12)
  - Television--Network Story, 1991 (Box 12)
  - Television--News programs, 1980-1986; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Television--Northern Telecom, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Television--PBS, 1981-1996; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Television--Prime time, 1975 (Box 12)
  - Television--Quaker Oats, 1987 (Box 12)
  - Television--R.T. French/Gerber, 1983 (Box 12)
  - Television--Sinutab--Game shows, 1983 (Box 13)
  - Television--Social responsibility, 1972 (Box 13)
  - Television--Southland Corporation, 1989 (Box 13)
  - Television--Specials, 1963-1991; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Television--Sports, 1985 (Box 13)
  - Television--Sports--Kodak, 1982 (Box 13)
  - Television--Sports--NFL, 1984-1989; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Television--Syndication, 1986-1987 (Box 13)
  - Television--TV Terms, 1976 (Box 13)
  - Television--Warner-Lambert, 1985 (Box 13)
  - Videocassette players, 1977 (Box 13)
  - Videocassette recorders, 1975-1993; 6 folders (Box 13)
  - ViewData, 1978 (Box 13)
  - Warner-Lambert, 1984 (Box 13)
  - Warner-Lambert--Trident, 1991 (Box 13)
  - Yankelovich Clancy Schulman, 1992-1993; 2 folders (Box 13)
  - Yankelovich Group, 1987 (Box 13)
  - Yankelovich Skelly White, 1970-1981; 2 folders (Box 13)